Alex Haras

alex.m.haras@gmail.com https://alexharas.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexharas

GitHub: https://github.com/al-haras

Career Profile

Build & Release/DevOps Engineer with experience improving build pipelines, and release processes. Works to create an environment where developers thrive, resulting in higher quality code and increased release frequency. Focused on implementation of automation, security checks, alerting and infrastructure-as-code where possible for existing environments and planning new projects. Additionally experienced in securing and auditing applications, cloud environments and internal corporate networks.

Technical Proficiencies:

Platforms: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Linux Servers (Ubuntu, RedHat, CentOS, Amazon Linux), VMWare ESXi, Azure, Hybrid Environments (Cloud/On-Prem), Salesforce Commerce Cloud, MuleSoft ESB/Anypoint

Tools: Bash, Git, Python, Jenkins, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, Maven, Grunt, Terraform, Tenable, Nessus, CVEs, Docker, Slack, PagerDuty

Professional Experience

Build & Release Engineer | Serena & Lily, Sausalito, CA

September 2019 – Current

Largely focused on working with Front End/eCommerce (Salesforce Commerce Cloud) and Back End teams to help identify and alleviate bottlenecks in the build and release process. This allows more frequent and higher quality changes to our production environments. Lead engineer responsible for PCI-DSS compliance. Conducts security audits of new features to our platform, applications and internal networks

- Refactored existing Back End Jenkins pipelines into a more dynamic and scalable CI/CD solution that is used in building services and features created by developers. This allows for new projects to be deployed without requiring the manual creation of new Jenkins pipelines.
- Identified a need of the Front End team to have additional development environments. Worked to implement a new Git branching strategy and created build pipelines, accommodating the necessary changes to the existing workflow.
 Completion of this project allowed developers to work on multiple releases simultaneously unhindered by previous limitations.
- Worked to add SonarCloud into existing CI/CD pipelines (Jenkins/MuleSoft ESB/Netsuite/Salesforce Commerce Cloud)
 to help identify and correct vulnerabilities, reduce duplication, and increase overall code quality in the existing and
 future codebase. Used in identifying and fixing issues and ensuring pull requests to development and production
 environments pass quality gate checks.
- Built company incident response using PagerDuty with Slack integration to proactively notify the Technology team of
 any issues that may be occurring. Alerts received for MuleSoft errors, integration problems, site performance issues,
 and store outages affecting Cisco Meraki equipment are setup to notify their respective teams via Slack and create Jira
 tickets.
- Took the lead on company-wide PCI-DSS Compliance. Implemented Tenable to scan and responsible for providing summary with corrective actions on a monthly basis. Worked to patch and update all infrastructure to prepare for PCI-DSS scans that occur quarterly, as well as working with VP of Technology to complete the PCI – Self Assessment Questionnaire.
- Worked with VP of Technology and Legal team to create a Security Incident Response Plan with standard operating
 procedures for investigation, response actions, mitigation and notification of stakeholders in the event of a security
 related incident.

Provides managed support services for 50+ clients. Scope includes Tier II and Tier I tickets (when applicable) and assisting in current projects for on-boarding new clients or migrating existing clients to new environments.

- Worked to assist Projects Engineers in migrating Microsoft Exchange 2012 users to Microsoft 365 for multiple clients.
- Migration of legacy applications and servers from existing VMs hosted in VMWare ESXi and vSphere to AWS.
- Regularly work using Cisco Meraki to modify Firewall rules and port-forwarding that is needed for vendors, adjustments to current VLANs, as well as managing site-to-site VPN connections.

Service Desk Associate | Fujitsu, Richardson, TX

July 2016 - April 2017

Responsible for supporting end-users within Fujitsu's Alliance Data Services contract.

- Managed user authentication, company share drives, folder permissions, Group Policy, and soft clients (desktop environments) using Active Directory, Group Policy Objects, and Citrix XenDesktop.
- Worked to ensure users were able to access needed financial data within their IBM Mainframe using RACF to manage user permissions and authentication.
- Responsible for correctly triaging reports of network and server outages and forwarding Emergency tickets to their respective teams.

Certifications

Amazon Web Services (AWS) – Solutions Architect – Associate May 2019 – May 2022

Education

Associate in Computer Programming (In Progress) - GPA: 4.0

Spring 2016 - Fall 2017

Tarrant County College, Fort Worth, TX